three things I like about the Nordic
Track commercial 2450 treadmill of the
3.6 CHP motor the foldability and the
fact that there's tons of Versatility
with a minus 3% decline a 12% incline
and a top speed of 12 mph if you're in
the market for a new high-tech treadmill
you might want to take some notes cuz we
got a whole lot to talk about today
let's get right to
[Music]
it
what's up y'all it's Jake back in the
barbing garage gym and for today's video
I've got the Nordic Track commercial
2450 treadmill in for review if you
don't know how this works in this video
today I'm going to tell you a lot of
information but specifically we're going
to talk about some money we're going to
talk about some pros and cons some
features and who should or maybe should
not purchase this treadmill now before I
do that I got to let you know we
reviewed a ton of treadmills on barb.
and we went ahead and came came up with
our own best list of all of our top
picks on the market so if you want to
check that out all you got to do is
search barbin best treadmills that list
is going to pull up and you can find out
for yourself which ones that we like the
best now since Nordic Track did in fact
revamp this treadmill I want to take one
quick second and just kind of talk about
the changes from their previous 2021
model first of all the overall aesthetic
is just completely different if you go
and look at some pictures you can just
tell right off the bat these are
basically two different treadmills and
one of the first things here is the
touchcreen all right so on the 2021
model it was a 14-in touchscreen but
this one it's a 22-in touchscreen and
that whole monitor right there will
actually tilt and rotate 360° while with
the previous one just kind of barely
tilted within the actual console the
2021 model had a lot more storage it had
a storage tray underneath the console
and and the cup holders were deeper now
I personally like the fact that that
tray is not there it kind of gives you
more leg room when you're running but
you having those deeper cup holders
honestly would would be pretty nice 2021
model also had built-in pulse sensors
which I think that's something they
should not have gotten rid of because it
would prevent you from having to go and
buy your own heart rate monitor just to
get an accurate reading on your heart
rate obviously but then also on your
burned calories so I kind of wish they
would have kept that now the 2021 model
also had 4.0 CHP motor while this one
has a 3.6 Honestly though I don't think
that's you know a big enough gap for you
to really be able to tell a difference
and then lastly that old model actually
had adjustable cushioning while this one
you know the cushioning is just
basically always turned on so now that
we're done with that let's go ahead and
talk about what I like and there's
plenty to like about it so 3.6 CHP motor
it's pretty strong all right now CHP
stands for constant horsepower so if you
see a treadmill that has just HP well
that's just talking about basically that
Peak Performance and it's not always
going to be at 3.6 so the fact that this
is CHP constant horsepower that's going
to be really nice for you know people
who run specifically and I already
mentioned some of this but I really do
love the fact that this is a foldable
treadmill you know other options like
the x22i you know it it doesn't fold and
that's just not the best for everybody
so if you're tight on space that's going
to be pretty solid for you there's also
a lot of ver versatility and variety
within your workouts so you have you
know a minus 3% decline a Max incline of
12% and a top speed of 12 mph so you can
have you know some Hill work you can
just bust out some Sprints whatever you
want to do you can basically get it done
on the 2450 also love you know the 22-in
touchscreen monitor it's really big
right there in your face you can follow
along to all your IIT workouts speaking
of IIT it's fully integrated right here
so many workouts that it's almost
overwhelming for you to choose from and
during those trainer Le workouts with
IIT on the treadmill and all the cardio
ones your trainer is actually going to
adjust you know your speed incline and
decline automatically for you based on
each individual class you can always
override it but I really like the fact
that you know that is a feature that way
you know you're always being pushed and
you don't really become complacent with
your own workouts another thing here is
that the 2450 actually has active pulse
technology so what that is basically if
you head over to the Nordic Track
website you purchase their heart rate
monitor it's about 100 bucks your
treadmill is going to pair up with that
and it's going to also adjust everything
to you know basically keep your heart in
the optimal heart rate zone which is
pretty cool it's not you know if it
notices that you're you know pushing too
hard it's going to dial it back a little
bit and just kind of keep you in that
optimal range now with those additional
IIT classes because there's a ton
there's like 16,000 of them there's so
many for you to choose from remember you
can rotate that monitor and you can
actually you know hop onto the ground
bust out your dumbbells your yoga mat
really whatever it is and you can follow
along to those workouts and you don't
have to stream from your phone or tablet
or whatever so that's really nice too
and similar to the other Nordic Track
equipment you do have Bluetooth
capabilities for your heart rate monitor
your phone your headphones speaker
that's pretty nice right there now I
know I just said a lot of things and
I've you know I'm I'm pretty pumped
about this treadmill it's really nice
but there are a few things that might
not be too crazy about first thing is
the price this is a luxury treadmill it
is high-tech so you're going to have to
pay that luxury price tag it's about
2,800 bucks now there's some other
variables that can make it more
expensive that I'll detail in just a
second don't worry but they might be out
of your wheelhouse right there now
you're also going to have to pay for IIT
to really get the most out of this
treadmill so either 40 bucks a month or
one of the three different yearly plans
that I'm going to break down you know
again just a second that's something
you're going to have to do I mean
there's no pre-loaded workouts on here
there's a manual option but you're
really just not getting the most out of
this especially with those automatic
adjustments the 1.9 in rollers might not
be you know ideal for everybody
specifically you know long dist Runners
and you hardcore sprinters so definitely
keep that in mind you know basically
rollers are going to determine overall
lifespan of the belt and actually the
treadmill so if you are dedicated
longdistance Runner or Sprinter you're
going to want to Target something over 2
in you know regarding those rollers so
definitely keep that in mind and then if
you're somebody who you know really just
wants a super high incline remember this
is 12% that's pretty solid but there's
other treadmills some that are cheap
that have a 15% incline and then if you
really want you know like a hardcore
workout with the incline might want to
go after that x22 or the
x32i cuz they have a 40%
[Music]
incline okay so as promised I'm going to
expand a little bit on money now
remember once again the Nordic Track
commercial 2450 treadmill has a starting
price tag of 2,800 bucks but unless you
just want to go after you know $40 IIT
membership plan plan you can tack on you
know an additional $400 700 or $900 for
the one two or threeyear IIT plan
respectively now obviously that really
drives up that price tag but as you can
see you know you can go to their website
and go through all the options it'll
show you exactly how much money you're
saving and it's a significant amount so
if you are you know committed you think
you're you know really going to enjoy
that IIT plan it's probably going to be
worth you know tacking on that
additional money up front now it comes
with a 10 year warranty on the frame two
years on parts and one year on labor but
you can spend an extra 300 bucks and in
addition to the 10year warranty on the
framework you're going to get 5 years on
Parts and four years on labor now you
can also go after you know the extended
maintenance plan for an extra 450 bucks
now you're only going to get an extra
two years on parts and two years on
labor but for those three years you're
going to get you know basically not free
but you're going to have a 15-point
checklist somebody from Nordic Track IIT
they're going to come out and basically
just make sure that your treadmill is
performing at its highest capacity so
that's going to be pretty cool too now
also if you want somebody you know to
come out and assemble your treadmill for
you and put it in your desired location
that's an extra 300 bucks you might you
know deem worthy of spending so the Max
total you could spend on this treadmill
is right around 4,600 bucks and Nordic
Track does offer financing directly
through them over a 39 month span and
one of the cool things about it is that
you know as you're selecting your
add-ons and everything you'll notice
that change in real time so you already
know you know what you're going to have
to pay before you actually you know make
that purchase now considering you all
the luxury features that the 2450 has I
think that's a pretty solid it's an okay
price tag I guess compared to the rest
of the market but that being said you
can also find some other really good
treadmills for about a th000 bucks
cheaper one that comes to mind is the
soul f80 now that being said you know it
does have a weaker motor it's a 3.5 HP
rather than CHP remember once again
that's talking about Peak Performance
doesn't have any decline settings but it
does have a higher incline of 15% and
the rollers are bigger they're 2.36 in
rather than 1.9 so it's actually you
probably going to be better suited for
those dedicated sprinters and
long-distance Runners now if you really
want to save some money then you might
want to Target a treadmill like the
Horizon
t101 treadmill is right around $700
right now but you know it the incline
caps out at 10% and the speed caps out
at 10 mph so yes it's you know
significantly cheaper but you're also
you missing out on some pretty solid
features but okay let's say you know you
really want to stick with Nordic Track
you just don't want to spend you know
$2800 on the 2450 now you could always
go after the EXP 7i it's about 1,300
bucks but probably the most comparable
that they have is going to be the 1750
we're really high on that treadmill it's
a really solid tread M about 400 bucks
cheaper and all the specs are the exact
same exp 7i that's not the case but
really the only thing different with the
1750 is that the touchscreen monitor is
actually 14 in rather than 22 in so like
I said y'all I mean this price tag it's
honestly pretty solid considering you
know what you're getting out of this
treadmill it just depends on really what
you're looking for
specifically so as I mentioned earlier
there are oodles and oodles of classes
available from IIT on your 22in
touchcreen monitor right here and you
know these are not just tailored to
cardio you know there's strength
training yoga meditation there there's a
whole lot going on and I really like
that you know if you're somebody who
thrives off having you know a trainer
having a coach you know lead you along
the way you're going to love it too and
the great thing is you know all your
stats are going to be saved you know
directly on your monitor but you also
have the IIT companion app you can
download on your phone or your tablet
and this is going to allow you to either
you know a stream those classes from
your phone or tablet but also anything
you do on the treadmill and phone vice
versa they're basically intertwined and
all of your stats all of your history
all of your progression I mean
everything you've done you know looking
at your workout history over a week
month year looking at all your programs
you've done all the trophies you've
earned from the various challenges that
are available they're all synced up
together and that's just a really great
thing and it's great for anybody who
likes to log their workouts and really
just track their progression over
time now the 2450 does have a little bit
of plastic mixed into the framework but
for the most part it is made of steel
and honestly when you're running even at
you know some of those top end speed
really doesn't wobble it's pretty stable
which is obviously a good thing now the
foldability is awesome for anybody who's
tied on space and it has wheels that are
going to make it you know pretty
portable to be honest it does weigh 300
lb but you know as you're moving it it
to me at least it doesn't really feel as
if it weighs 300 lb which is a good
thing now the running surface measures
60 in in length and 20 in wide that's
okay you know it it's definitely more
narrow than some other treadmills you
know the x22i it's 22 in wide it's
honestly going to be fine 20 in but just
kind of keep that in mind if you want
something that's a little bit wider
remember do have that 3.6 CHP motor
which is plenty strong to you know give
you a grueling workout and to last for
you know a hefty amount of time I guess
you could say the 1.9 in rollers are
okay overall but it would be nice if
they were a little bit bigger and this
does have a weight capacity of 300 lb
which is honestly really respectable now
regarding the actual specs remember you
do have that 22-in touchscreen monitor
it's going to you know Grant you access
to all the available IIT classes and in
addition to the IIT you know Google Maps
is also also integrated on here as well
I honestly love that you can choose
literally any city in the world that you
want to go to and the adjustments are
going to happen automatically you know
based on the lay of the land in whatever
City that you're in in addition to
obviously those IIT classes where the
trainer automatically does that for you
you do have a fan that's in between the
two cup holders that's going to you know
help keep you cool and you have two 3-in
speakers right underneath the monitor as
well that are going to you know provide
ample sound for your trainer and for
your actual music there's a lot of cool
music that's loaded on there they
refresh it all the time they have the
oldies classic rock modern day hip-hop
whatever it is it's going to be right
there for you another cool thing right
here as well is that on either side of
the monitor you're going to notice you
have buttons for you to you know adjust
the speed you can you know press five
for example on and for the incline as
well excuse me so with the speed you
know you can press five it'll take it to
5 mph but if you double tap it it'll go
to 5 and 1/2 miles per hour which is
really cool and then you also have your
your micro you know incremental
adjustments you can make with the arrows
that are located just underneath the
[Music]
monitor all right so remember with the
2450 the deck you're working with you
know 60 in in length which is solid it's
pretty standard but it is a little bit
narrow compared to some other treadmills
it's 20 inches wide you know a lot of
them are 22 inches wide so definitely
just you know keep that in mind but it
is what it is now
the star of the show obviously I think
it goes without saying is just this 22in
touchscreen monitor and I just want to
show you guys kind of how everything
functions all right so whenever you
first log on I'm already logged in
obviously you have the choice of you
know choosing you know which profile to
log in with so you have your profile and
you can have four additional profiles so
everybody will have their own you know
specific you know this is my past seven
days working out it's going to have that
you know for everybody you individually
which is cool now as you scroll through
I mean it's going to have you know this
one's a beginner you know time crunch
challenge this is all based on strength
right so remember you can rotate this
guy 360° and it's already tilted back
right now you can tilt it a little bit
more forward it's going be really great
you know you can hop on the floor do
some additional workouts now you have
your featured now right here there's the
latest from iFit these are all different
challenges okay up next for you quick
strength you know training in the
Balkans there's a whole lot right here
there's different challenges recommended
workouts and the cool thing is you know
there's this beginner running series and
it shows you there's 30 different
workouts right there so basically you're
going to get a little trophy it's going
to go on your trophy case right there
whenever you complete anything like that
okay so you can also browse back
category right here running walking mind
you know I told you there's some
meditation there's some yoga stuff cross
training active recovery IIT honestly
just knocks it out the park with all
their stuff there's a whole lot going
going on right here so go to your
calendar right here and just kind of
show some different workouts you've done
go to create I love this feature right
here this is where the Google Maps comes
into play all right so I clicked it
takes us to Cape Town South Africa and
basically while you're here you can zoom
out a little bit it kind of takes there
we go um and you can literally map out
everything you can pick anywhere you
want you can instantly change to
different cities across the world as
well so you can go to browse again right
here we'll go ahead and exit that and
this is just you showing you more of the
IIT Library
so it typically doesn't take this long
of course since I'm shooting this video
it's going to take a little bit longer
rights so basically this is just more of
the same of how it popped up on the
homepage just all this different stuff I
mean there's road to recovery top five
series collection treadmill walking for
Fitness you know there's it's almost
overwhelming as I mentioned so I just
want to showcase really quick kind of
how fast this 3.6 CHP motor just kind of
responds to everything and kind of just
how it overall performs all right so you
don't have any pre-loaded workouts but
you do have the manual option if you
don't want to follow along to anything
it's going to allow you to warm up
really quick and it's going to Showcase
your speed distance time elapse your
estimated calories burn because remember
you don't have any built-in pulse
sensors right here but you know if you
do have a heart rate monitor that's
going to show up you know accordingly
and then your incline pops up right here
all right so we're going to go and in
the warmup really quick
now it's just going to have a basic you
know quarter mile track length right
here but just want to show you really
quick all right so it starts at one
miles per hour click on
12 takes you it takes a couple seconds
but that's going to allow you to kind of
you know adjust your body as you're
running that's pretty quick it's kind of
loud so you know keep that in mind
family members roommates and everything
but that's pretty quick now we're going
to do that double tap feature
a double tap
five and it slows down pretty quick as
well just for noise purposes I'm going
to go back down to one now look click 12
right
here already going up it's pretty quick
I mean yeah there's some other ones that
might respond a little bit quicker but
honestly that's pretty solid and it like
I said same thing with the speed kind of
allows you to adjust rather than justop
going straight to 12 mph or you know 12%
in line and then you can
just back down to zero and it's going to
do the same thing so you do have your
volume buttons right here whenever
there's music playing you have your
incline and your speed settings right
here obviously you have your start and
stop button and then you have your fan
buttons right
here keep you nice and cool as you're
working out as that intensity starts to
ramp up go ahead and stop right there
and you know whenever you're done
working out I definitely recommend you
flip the off switch back
here before you unplug it that way you
know you don't want it to kind of get
messed up or anything but definitely
unplug it that way you know you can
avoid a power surge and power goes out
whatever you're not going to fry any of
your any of your internal components
right here but cool thing remember it is
a foldable treadmill so whenever you're
done working out just simply lift up
back here there's kind of a little bit
of a plastic I guess handle you could
call it it's not actually a handle but
it works as it or you can just grab
actual belt right here and just lift up
up you do it one hand the hydraulic lift
system right there basically just takes
over and it's going to lock into place
and as you can see there's a diagram
right here you you can simply put your
foot there I usually lift up a little
bit and then you can even let go and
it'll just take care of the rest for you
and your wheels are exposed whenever you
fold this up sorry and I'm going up and
down up and down on you but your wheels
are exposed right here so all you got to
do is just simply lift back right here
and then you're able to move it around
on those wheels so if you're tight on
Space it's a really good option for you
okay so when we talk about you know who
should purchase this treadmill I think
the 2450 really is just you know
tailored for those who want a trainer to
lead them through their cardio workout
and also anybody who just wants you know
a super techsavvy piece of cardio
equipment this checks off both of those
boxes at the same time you know if
you're a long-distance Runner I think
you're going to want to Target a
treadmill that has larger sized rollers
remember this is 1.9 you're going to
want anything 2.25 to two 5 in in
diameter just you know for longevity
purposes and then also you know this is
a expensive purchase you know if you
don't want to spend $2,800 on a
treadmill you don't have to I promise
there's other ones out there that are
solid as well and they're definitely
going to get the job done plus if you
just want you know a basic treadmill to
hop on and burn some extra calories
every day or every other day you can
definitely find a way way more basic
option
[Music]
all right well that's a wrap for today's
review over the Nordic Track commercial
2450 treadmill I really love how they
revamped this model right here you know
the touchscreen monitor is really easy
to navigate the interface is really
quick you can rotate it hop on the floor
and do some additional workouts
automatic adjustments are clutch for you
know many reasons you know it's going to
prevent you from being complacent during
your workouts just remember this is an
expensive purchase because of all those
luxury features features and the rollers
are a little undersized for anybody
who's a dedicated longdistance Runner
that's all I got for y'all today I hope
this video was really helpful and I was
able to break down everything in full
about this treadmill as always say
posted for my next video but for now
head over to Barb and.com cuz we have a
full written article about this
treadmill all you got to do is search
barbend Nordic Track commercial 2450
treadmill review it's going to pull
right up for you you can go over every
single thing we talked about here today
I'll catch youall next
time
[Music]
everything